

Ana Maria Roberts

Portfolio: www.anaroberts.com

UX/UI + **Product** + **Brand designer** with knowledge in **HTML, CSS and JavaScript** with an MA in Design by Creating Practices, that can provide successful creative solutions to customers and businesses, based on empathy, user centred design research, design thinking processes, innovation, and aesthetics.

Committed to be part of every aspect of the design process - end to end design - willing to help, learn and collaborate with others.

Experience

Senior Product designer, UK. 12/2018 – Present.

- Design, produce and create user friendly products end to end for the most recognised children's brands around the world to deliver new products to the market. Such as, Mattel, Little tikes, LOL, Rainbow High, Paw patrol etc...
- Research, analyse and create successful designs according to the market and business needs.
- Create brands and style guides to bring new on trend aesthetics ensuring identity and values are being kept.
- Contributed to the development and optimization of processes to bring straight forward critical paths considering quality, cost and resources.
- Working on a fast-paced environment, delivering successful results considering deadlines and business requirements.
- Micromanaging the design team and ensuring we deliver eye catching and functional products/services.
- Contribute to the business to innovate and stand out in order to expand and ensuring consumers there are happier too.
- Communicate with teams oversees and licensors to research analyse and optimise our products.

Senior Product designer-UK. 12/2014 - 12/2018.

- Similar to my current role I researched, designed and created children's products for the main retailers in the UK.
- Based on resources I contributed to innovate and build up communication with far east to deliver user friendly products and services.
- Improved branding and created style guides and product/services for Aldi EU and UK.
- Oversee and approved products to be launched considering licensors, stake holders and business goals....

Quality control assistant - Lighting, UK. 04/2013 - 10/2013

- Collaborated and helped management to optimise processes, oversee tasks and solve issues to protect luxury products that were being delivered to customers.
- Worked within a small team that helped me to escalate my English to a professional level within a business environment.

Education

- CareerFoundry, Front end Development, Specialization, Present.
- CareerFoundry, **UX Immersion**, 07/2023.
- CareerFoundry, Intro to UX Design, 10/2022.
- Liverpool Hope University, **MA in Design** by Creative Practices, 01/2014. Honours degree
- The University of Sheffield, Academic English. 2013
- El Bosque University, BA Industrial Design/Product design. 2012
- Colombian Airforce, Human Rights. 2003

Contact

Preston, UK.
------@gmail.com

Skills & Tools

Personal skills:

- Leadership skills
- Empathic
- Problem solver
- Proactive
- Committed
- Supportive

UX Skills:

- Design thinking
- Competitor Analysis
- Emotional design
- Personas
- Information architecture,
- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- Usability testing
- Branding

Tools

- Adobe creative cloud
- Figma
- Marvel
- HTML, JavaScript and CSS
- **3D:** Rhinoceros, Solid Works Vray, Blender.

Languages

- English Fluent
- Spanish Fluent